So, there's one other interesting thing we can do with find.
我们可以使用 find 来做另一个有趣的事情
And going back to the original description of find, we said,
回到 find 语句的原始描述上
well, find returns the first position, there might other occurrences. And
find 定位到目标出现的第一个位置 目标可能在其他位置也会出现
we might want to find those other occurrences. The way to find
我们或许想要找到那些其他位置出现的目标
those other occurrences is, we can actually pass in an extra
找到那些目标的方法是
parameter. So, instead of just passing in one string, we can
我们可以传送一个额外的参数 我们不只传送一个字符串参数
pass in the second parameter, which is going to be a
可以加第二个参数
number. Then when we pass in a number what find will output
它会是一个数字参数 当我们添加了数字参数之后
is the number of the position in the search
find 最后输出的就是 目标字符串在搜索字符串中出现的位置数字
string, where the target string appears, the first occurrence after
是那个位置之后 目标第一次出现的地方
that position. So, it'll give the first occurrence where
所以显示的是
the target string appears in the search string, but starting
目标字符串在搜索字符串中第一次出现的地方 但是需要从
from whatever position we pass in this number. So,
我们输入的数值开始算起
if we pass in zero, well, it would start from
因此如果我们输入0
the beginning, that would mean the same thing as
它就会从开始进行搜索
the original find. If we pass in the position here,
这就和初始 find 语句有一样的效果 如果我们输入这个位置
it would start from there and would still output
则会从那里开始搜索
the same value we found before. If we start from
仍然会输出和我们之前得到的一样的结果
here, well then, it wouldn't find this occurrence, because this
如果我们从这里开始 就不会找到这个显示
occurrence starts after that position, it would find this one.
因为我们的搜索范围在这个显示之后 此次搜索会找到这个
So, here's an example. We'll use this quote
这里有个例子
attributed to George Danton during the French Revolution. Translated
我们可以使用 George Danton 在法国大革命时期的名言
loosely, it means audacity, more audacity, always audacity.
简单的翻译一下就是说 大胆一些 更大胆一些 一直要很大胆
I should mention that Danton was actually executed, so
我要说 Danton 最后被处死了
whether you want to follow this advice or
因此是否听从他的意见
not depends on how you think things worked out
还要取决于你对他的结局的看法
for him. But if we do a find
但是如果我们使用 find 语句来搜索
with danton, passing in audace with no extra parameter,
Danton 的这句话 输入不加其它参数的 audace
we'll get position five which is the position
我们可以得到字符串 audace 出现的位置 是数字 5
where audace starts. The first occurrence of audace
audace 第一次出现的位置已经找到
is found. [NOISE] If we pass in a number as well, well if we pass in zero,
如果我们也输入一个数字参数 如果我们输入数字 0
we'll also get five. That's because starting from
那么结果依然是5  因为从0开始进行搜索
position zero, we find audace at position five. If
我们会找到 audace 出现的位置5
we pass in the number five, we'll still
如果我们输入数字 5
get five as the result, starting from position five,
我们依然得到5这个结果 从位置5开始搜索
we find audace at position five. If we
我们找到 audace 出现在位置5上
pass in a number higher than five, let's pass
如果我们输入比5大的数字
in six, well now find is looking for
比如6 现在则是从位置6开始搜索
an occurrence starting from position six, which is here.
也就是这儿
Instead of finding the first occurrence of audace,
这个时候我们就找不到第一个出现的 audace
it'll find the first one that occurs after position
会找到在位置6以后出现的 audace
six, which is the one here at position 25.
它在这里 在位置25出现
Let's just print out the string from position six
我们从位置6搜索输出一下字符串 来证实一下我们的想法
to confirm that. So, printing from position six to the end, we see that the
从位置6搜索到结尾
quote is udace, encore. And so on.
我们看到搜索结果就是 udace encore 等等
I'll spare you from my poor French pronunciation,
请原谅我的法语发音不好 所以这里不念出来了
and that's why it found audace at
这也就解释了我们为什么会找到
this location, which is position 25. The result
位于位置25的这个 audace 字符串
always counts from the beginning of the
输出结果总是从字符串的开头算起的
original string. Position 25 of the original string,
从字符串开头算起的第25位
which is where it found the second occurrence of audace. So if we pass in 25.
是第二个 audace 出现的地方  所以如果我们输入25
We'll get 25 as the output, finding the position where this occurrence occurs.
输出结果就是25 也就是第二个 audace 出现的位置
If we pass in 26, now it will start searching at position 26 which is the u
如果我们输入26 就会从第26位开始搜索 也就是 u 这个位置
here. We'll find at position 47. The final occurrence of audace. So,
我们就会找到位置47 也就是最后一个 audace 出现的位置
seeing the string from position 47 to the end,
也就是从位置47到结尾的字符串
starting from here, we see that. Now, we're starting
从这里开始 我们已经看到了
from position 48, which is this u. We'll get
现在 我们从位置48开始搜索 也就是 u 这个位置
as our output, negative one. And that's because, although
输出结果是-1 这是因为
the string occurs many times in the string danton,
虽然 audace 在 Danton 这句名言里出现了很多次
it doesn't occur at all starting from position 48.
但是从位置48之后并没有再出现过
And so, the output of find, when the target
因此 当在搜索字符范围内没有出现目标字符串的时候
string is not found in the search string, is negative
find 语句的输出结果就是 -1
one and that's true if we start from position 48, we
这就验证了如果从位置48开始搜索的话
don't find the target string at all in the search string.
我们在搜索范围内根本就找不到目标字符串